<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Dice Roller</string>
    <string name="name">Lukasz Blachnicki</string>
    <string name="image_placeholder">star icon</string>
    <string name="bio">
        Mickiewicz was born in Nowogródek in Lithuania and always thought of the region as his homeland. He studied at Vilnius University and went on to teach at the provincial school in Kaunas. He was among the founders of the secret patriotic Towarzystwo Filomatow / Philomaths\' Society. He is known chiefly for the poetic drama Dziady (Forefathers\' Eve) and the national epic poem Pan Tadeusz. His other influential works include Konrad Wallenrod and Grażyna. All these served as inspiration for uprisings against the three imperial powers that had partitioned the Polish–Lithuanian Commonwealth out of existence. Mickiewicz was born in the Russian-partitioned territories of the former Grand Duchy of Lithuania, which had been part of the Polish–Lithuanian Commonwealth, and was active in the struggle to win independence for his home region. After, as a consequence, spending five years exiled to central Russia, in 1829 he succeeded in leaving the Russian Empire and, like many of his compatriots, lived out the rest of his life abroad. He settled first in Rome, then in Paris, where for a little over three years he lectured on Slavic literature at the Collège de France. He died, probably of cholera, at Constantinople in the Ottoman Empire, where he had gone to help organize Polish forces to fight Russia in the Crimean War. After serving five years of exile to Russia, Mickiewicz received permission to go abroad in 1829. On 1 June that year, he arrived in Weimar.[22] By 6 June he was in Berlin, where he attended lectures by the philosopher Hegel.[22] In February 1830 he visited Prague, later returning to Weimar, where he received a cordial reception from the writer, scientist and politician Goethe.[22] He then continued on through Germany all the way to Italy, which he entered via the Alps\' Splügen Pass.[22] Accompanied by an old friend, the poet Antoni Edward Odyniec, he visited Milan, Venice, Florence and Rome.[22][23] In August that same year (1830) he went to Geneva, where he met fellow Polish Bard Zygmunt Krasiński.[23] During these travels he had a brief romance with Henrietta Ewa Ankwiczówna [pl], but class differences again prevented his marrying his new love.[23] Finally about October 1830 he took up residence in Rome, which he declared "the most amiable of foreign cities."[23] Soon after, he learned about the outbreak of the November 1830 Uprising in Poland, but he would not leave Rome until the spring of 1831.[23]</string>
    <string name="what_is_your_nickname">What is your nickname?</string>
    <string name="done">Done!</string>
</resources>